Jinsong Liu

UX Designer / sylvesterlau.com

Jinsong Liu (Sylvester Lau) is a multidisciplinary designer from Guangzhou, China. He worked for three years on digital transformation in finance, retail and e-learning, and is currently studying Master Student on User Experience Design. Holding a continued interest in human-technology relationships, he aspired to become a full-stack designer. His work values collaboration, measurable results but also appreciates the complex nature and unexpected processes.

EDUCATION

2020 — 2021 University of the Arts London London, United Kingdom

User Experience Design, Master of Arts

2020 — 2021 Guangdong University of Technology Guangzhou, China

Industrial Design, Bachelor of Engineering

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 **UX Designer (Master's Degree Project)** Moley Robotics

London, United Kingdom

We collaborated with the world's first robotic kitchen to design a systematic research method and 16 robot modes examining human-robot interactions, supporting robot industry's product design and evaluation.

2021 **UX Designer (Master's Degree Project)** Victoria and Albert Museum

London, United Kingdom

We worked with the V&A Museum to devise an an immersive, interactive and generative VR experience of their fascinating online collection, enhancing its educational and research functions.

2018 — 2019 Retail Project Design Lead Runwise Co.

Guangzhou, China

I led the design team of a digitalisation project for Kungfu Restaurant Co, China's top Chinese fast-food brand. Collaborated with project managers, engineers, and the marketing team, we delivered an omnichannel online order system (App, Kiosk, Dashboard) with a design system. The project raised online customer retention to 55% and helped the company ready for the unexpected COVID-19 pandemic.

2017 — 2018 UX Designer Runwise Co.

Guangzhou, China

I crafted interfaces, illustrations and infographics for Refuel, an e-learning app on lean-product, agile management and other skills.

2016 Interaction Design Intern ETU Design

Guangzhou / Shenzhen / Hong Kong, China

I collaborated with senior designers and user researchers to design user flow, wireframes interfaces. Clients included China Mobile HK, China Merchants Bank.

sylvester.lau@outlook.com

+44 07513 880183

130 Elephant Road, London SE17 1EX

View LinkedIn profile

LANGUAGE

English

IELTS Academic 7.5 / CEFR C1

Chinese / Cantonese

Native Speaker

AWARDS

CEP's Featured Project

Individual project "Bubble Trouble" was featured in a column of the <u>Complexity</u> Education Project.

WeChat Smart Retail Services, 2018

Team project "Kungfu Order" received the Wechat Mini App annual award

SKILLS

User Interviews

Interactive Prototyping

Design System

Data-driven Design

Product Strategy

System Thinking

Design Management

User Testing

Life Learner

T00LS

Figma / Sketch
Physical Model
HTML / CSS / JavaScript
Always trying new tools